‎我在澳大利亞的陽光海岸長大
I grew up on the Sunshine Coast in Australia,
‎也就是說 ‎我和我的家人從未遠離過大海
which means my family and I were never far from the ocean.
‎我們不是在海里 就是在海上
If we weren't in it, we were on it.
‎我們其實就住在船上 它叫船屋號
We practically lived on our boat, Home Abroad.
‎雖然爸爸媽媽和我們四個孩子 ‎蝸居在里面有點擁擠
It was a tight fit, Mum, Dad, and the four of us kids,
‎但只要一家人在一起就很開心
but we were happy because we were together.
‎到了晚上 媽媽會給我們講 ‎天上的外星人的故事
At night, Mum would tell us stories about a starman in the sky,
‎還有海浪聲伴我們入眠
then the waves would rock us to sleep.
‎我永遠不會忘記 ‎第一次獨自開船的經歷
I'll never forget the first time I sailed by myself,
‎忘不了當風鼓動船帆時 ‎那油然而生的興奮
the rush of excitement when my sail caught the wind,
‎和大海的神奇魅力
the magic and the allure of the sea.
‎我當上了船長 ‎整個世界展現在我眼前
I was the captain and the whole world was in front of me,
‎等待著被發現
just waiting to be discovered.
‎我能聽到大海在呼喚我的名字
I could hear the ocean calling my name.
‎12歲的我 為之深深著迷
By the time I was 12, I was obsessed.
‎四年來 我一直在研究海洋和海浪
For four years, I studied the ocean, the waves,
‎學習一切關于帆船的知識
and learnt everything I could about sailing boats.
‎我做了三份兼職攢錢
I worked three part-time jobs and saved money,
‎夢想著有朝一日能駕帆船周游世界
because I dreamed that one day I would sail around the world.
‎逐夢大海
本WEB版外掛字幕由  風吹來的那片云  雙語合并
‎（試航 2009年9月 ‎太平洋 澳洲近海）
‎（鮑伊號）
‎杰絲 試航進展如何
Jess, how's the practice run going?
‎剛被一艘突然出現的貨船撞了
Cargo ship hit me. Came out of nowhere.
‎船進水了嗎
You taking on water?
‎沒有 看上去沒漏水 但桅桿斷了
No. No, doesn't look like it, but I've been dismasted.
‎為什么警報沒響
Why didn't the alarm go off?
‎把你的坐標給我
Okay, give me your coordinates.
‎南緯26度 25…
Uh, we're at 26 degrees, 25…
‎杰絲 穩住呼吸
Jess, breathe.
‎集中精神
Focus.
‎天啊 出什么事了
Oh, my God, what happened?
‎她沒事 跟一艘貨船撞了
She's okay. Collided with a cargo ship.
‎她被貨船撞了
She was hit by a cargo ship?
‎酷啊
Cool.
‎一點也不酷 湯姆
Not cool, Tom.
‎她不會有事吧
Is she gonna be all right?
‎-她一定不會有事的 回去睡覺 ‎-想得美
-I'm sure she'll be fine. Go back to bed. -As if.
‎杰絲 你受傷了嗎
Jess, are you hurt?
‎沒有 媽媽 我沒事
No, Mum, I'm fine.
‎真的 我保證
Really, I promise.
‎我們說好了的 不能撞上任何東西
Thought we agreed, no collisions.
‎我也不想啊
I couldn't help myself.
‎我能跟杰絲說話嗎 我想跟杰絲聊
Can I talk to Jess? I want to talk to Jess!
‎-讓我說幾句吧  ‎-等漢娜說完
-Oh, can I talk to her? -I haven't talked to her.
‎-那是海盜船嗎  ‎-她把坐標報錯了
-Jess, was it a pirate ship? -She's getting her coordinates wrong.
‎我要呼叫海岸警衛隊
Okay, come on. That's it. -I'm calling the Coast Guard.
‎別 會有一堆記者涌過來的
-Don't. Reporters will be lining the docks.
‎他們都等著看她失敗呢 ‎她不能一瘸一拐地回來
They are waiting for her to fail. She cannot come limping back in.
‎-你確定她的船還適合航海嗎  ‎-她認為可以
-Do we know if the boat's seaworthy? -She reckons it is.
‎-那個16歲的姑娘… ‎-杰絲需要確認她能獨立完成行程
-Oh, well, as long as the 16-year-old-- -Jess needs to know she can do this alone.
‎她離海岸只有32公里
She's only 20 miles from the shore.
‎想象一下 如果這時候 ‎她離最近的港口也有3200公里呢
Now imagine if she does this, and she's 2,000 miles from the nearest port.
‎我們會在碼頭等你 ‎也許情況沒那么糟
We'll be at the marina to meet you. It's probably not that bad in daylight.
‎謝謝你 艾米莉
Thanks, Em.
‎杰絲
Jess!
‎好了 聽到我說“迎風轉向”
Okay, so when I say tack,
‎我們就把帆轉向另一邊
we're gonna switch the sail to the other side.
‎準備好贏了嗎
You ready to win?
‎好了 我們開始吧
All right, guys, let's get started!
‎-嘿 杰絲 怎么了  ‎-我還沒準備好
Hey! Jess, what's wrong? -I'm not ready.
‎-沒有嗎  ‎-親愛的
-No? -Oh, sweetheart.
‎-你不想去了  ‎-還沒做好心理準備
-Don't want to go, kiddo? I think we're still finding our sea legs.
‎-好吧 ‎-我聽說你是奪冠熱門呢
-Fair enough. -Well, I heard you're the favorite to win.
‎是啊 也許吧
Yeah. Maybe.
‎來呀 杰絲
Come on, Jess!
‎不試試怎么知道 ‎海上是怎樣的景象呢
You won't know what's out there unless you try.
‎別跑太遠
No, no, not too far.
‎等等 艾米莉
Wait, Emily, wait!
‎快來 杰絲
Quick, Jess!
‎過來 好了
Come here. There you go.
‎杰西卡沃森唯一的試航提早結束 ‎證明反對她此行的人…
Jessica Watson's only sea trial has been cut short, proving her critics…
‎阿瑟頓 嘿 阿瑟頓
Atherton! Hey, Atherton!
‎他怎么就能過去
How come he's allowed down there?
‎-阿瑟頓 ‎-本
-Atherton. -Ben.
‎你們這幫人來這里干什么
Don't know what you lot think you're doing here.
‎我們來是因為…
Well, I guess we're here because…
‎（警察-粉紅號）
‎…居然有人要讓一個孩子 ‎開著一艘那么小的船出海
that boat is a shockingly tiny thing to send a child out to sea in.
‎-不光小 還很脆弱 ‎-別理他了
-It's pretty flimsy too. -Leave it.
‎趁火打劫的家伙
Vultures.
‎那就別讓他們得逞
Then don't feed them.
‎為什么不讓得逞
Why aren't we feeding vultures?
‎你姐姐嘗試做的事
It's not every day that someone
‎很少有像她這么年輕的人會去做
as young as your sister tries to do what she's doing.
‎這是一件大事 人們會有疑問
It's a big deal. People have questions, that's all.
‎這令她成了關注的焦點
Plus, it makes her a target.
‎成功了 就把她捧成英雄 ‎失敗了 悲劇故事也能大賣
If she succeeds, she's a hero. If she fails, well, tragedy sells.
‎她才十歲啊
She's ten.
‎他們在尋找弱點 別讓他們輕慢了你
They're looking for weakness. Don't let 'em treat you any different.
‎你是一名船長 明白嗎
You're a captain, got it?
‎好的 我是杰西卡的顧問 本布萊恩特
All right, I'm Ben Bryant, Jessica's advisor.
‎杰絲
Jess.
‎我是杰西卡沃森
I-- I'm Jessica Watson.
‎我計劃成為全世界最年輕的獨自完成
And, uh, I… I'm planning on being the youngest person
‎無間斷環球航海之旅的人
to sail around the world nonstop and unassisted.
‎昨晚發生了什么事
Jessica, what happened last night?
‎-發生了碰撞 ‎-是你的錯嗎
-There was a collision. -Were you at fault?
‎一艘貨船偏離了它的航道
A cargo ship detoured from its route.
‎杰西卡 ‎這是你唯一一次試航的第一夜
Jessica, this was night one of your only test run.
‎你無法平安在兩個港口之間往返 ‎又如何環游世界呢
How are you gonna make it around the world if you can't make it between two ports?
‎本 我們不是來聽你說話的 謝謝
Uh, and we're not here for you. Thanks, Ben.
‎我相信我可以
I believe I can.
‎你明白你要做的是什么嗎
You understand what you're in for?
‎那可是汪洋大海啊 ‎海浪有公寓樓那么高
Uh, we're talking open ocean, waves the size of apartment buildings,
‎風速130公里每小時
70-knot winds.
‎這就是航海界的珠穆朗瑪峰
I mean, this is the Mount Everest of sailing.
‎對 航線確實頗有挑戰性
Well, yes, the-- the route is challenging,
‎但我半輩子都在航海 所以我…
but, uh, I've sailed half my life, so I--
‎也就是只有幾年嘍
So a couple years then?
‎我已經完成了 ‎18520公里的里程數 我有資格
I've done the 10,000 nautical miles. I'm qualified.
‎而且我們做足了準備
And we've prepared.
‎她怎么能想到 ‎會有貨船連航海雷達都不看
How could she prepare for a cargo ship that ignores its radar?
‎那為什么在撞擊之前 ‎你的感應警報器沒向你示警
So why didn't your proximity alarms alert you before the crash?
‎我忘記把它打開了
-I forgot to turn them on.
‎沃森先生 沃森太太 ‎你們想必無法認同此種行為吧
Mr. and Mrs. Watson, surely you have reservations hearing that?
‎她犯了一個錯誤 我相信她不會再犯
She made a mistake. It's one I'm certain she won't make again.
‎你們不認為16歲太年輕了嗎
So you don't think 16 is too young?
‎我們憑什么否定她的夢想
Who are we to deny her her dreams?
‎她一直為之努力奮斗 ‎也證明了她有這個實力
She's worked hard and proven she can do this every step of the way.
‎那么 新的啟航日定在哪一天
So when is the new departure day?
‎我想應該在十月中旬之前出發吧
Uh, well, I guess we just have to leave by mid-October.
‎也就是兩周后 很樂觀啊 不是嗎
So two weeks. Hmm, optimistic, no?
‎那是南冰洋布滿冰山之前的 ‎最后一個窗口期
Well, it's the last window before the Southern Ocean's filled with icebergs.
‎杰西卡
Jessica!
‎如果官方讓你取消計劃呢
Well, what about calls by authorities to cancel altogether?
‎本 你有能力 ‎讓這個女孩平安回家嗎
Ben, are you the right person to bring this girl home?
‎我有經驗
Got a bit of experience.
‎但你在千禧杯比賽擔任船長時 ‎就曾失去一名船員
But as captain in the Millennium Cup, you lost one of your own crew members.
‎馬特特納
A Matt Turner.
‎嘿 夠了
Hey! That's enough.
‎-請讓我說完… ‎-不 我們聽夠了
-Well, let me finish-- -Nah. We're done here.
‎四年的努力換來這滿目瘡痍
Four years of hard work boils down to this.
‎我有查看航海雷達 但沒看見那艘船
Ben, I looked at the radar and I didn't see the ship.
‎我就是打了個盹兒 沒想到…
And it was just a short nap. So I didn't think that--
‎不 你根本沒有思考 ‎這是不負責任的行為 杰絲
No, you didn't think. It was irresponsible, Jess.
‎而且你老是報錯坐標
You know you kept getting your coordinates wrong too?
‎你的精神狀態至關重要
It's your state of mind that matters out there.
‎如果被閱讀障礙影響了判斷 ‎你會在大海中迷失的
If dyslexia takes over, you are lost in the middle of the ocean, mate.
‎好了 我們明白了
All right. All right, we get it.
‎你覺得我們能修好它嗎
Do you reckon we can fix it?
‎雖然狀況有點慘烈 但沒問題
Bit of a dog's breakfast, but… -Yeah,
‎它還有得救
there's some life left in her yet.
‎不過 修繕它是個大工程
I mean, these aren't small repairs, though.
‎我們既沒錢又沒人力 ‎也沒有合適的維修地點
We've got no money, no manpower, no location to even fix it.
‎不能找我的贊助人出資嗎
Yeah, but won't my sponsors help?
‎之前就換過一次桅桿 ‎不知道這回他們還愿不愿買單
Not sure they'll want to pay for a new mast twice over.
‎很多地方可以發揮一下主觀能動性 ‎比如給這張帆打個補丁 重復利用
We can get creative with a lot of it. You know, reuse this rig, patch where possible.
‎絕對不行 ‎必須從頭到腳修復到最佳狀態
Not a chance. We do it right, down to the smallest bolt.
‎-沒有資金怎么辦  ‎-那你就來年再去
But what if we can't get the money? -Then you wait another year.
‎-爸爸  ‎-安全最重要
-Dad! Your safety is the only thing that matters.
‎若沒有萬全的準備 ‎我很樂意取消這次航行
And I have no problem calling this off if things aren't done properly.
‎其實 也許我們就該干脆取消算了 ‎這次失敗算是敲響了警鐘
You know… maybe we should regardless. This has been quite the wake-up call.
‎-那是意外… ‎-別急著現在做決定
-No. It was an accident-- -Hey, no one's making any decisions now.
‎我們先等等看贊助人怎么說 ‎對吧 杰絲
Let's wait and see what the sponsors have to say first. Right, Jess?
‎對 是的
Yeah. Yeah, right.
‎去年的國家橄欖球聯賽 ‎總決賽贏家曼利海鷹隊
Last year's NRL Grand Final winners, the Manly Sea Eagles,
‎周末以34比6的大比分 ‎力挫墨爾本風暴
look set to take out the premiership again this year
‎曼利今年有望 ‎再度問鼎超級橄欖球聯賽
after thrashing the Melbourne Storm 34-6 over the weekend.
‎奪得總決賽的三連冠
This will be Manly's third consecutive Grand Final.
‎別忘了放學后打籃網球
Don't forget netball after school.
‎-看著我 然后… ‎-對 然后 開始
-Eyes on me. And… -Yep. And, go!
‎真棒
Oi, very good!
‎別以為冰箱里 ‎會有東西憑空出現 湯姆
Don't think anything new's gonna appear in there, Tom.
‎很好 你會把自己轉暈的
-Very good. -You're gonna make yourself dizzy.
‎我知道
-I know!
‎-打到你嘍  ‎-喂 別胡鬧
-Got you! -Oi! Cut it out!
‎-我接受采訪的話 有錢賺嗎  ‎-不夠多
-Would they pay me for interviews? -Not enough for repairs.
‎-杰西卡沃森的冒險就在她的家人… ‎-看
-Jessica Watson's adventure… -Jess, look!
…收拾好行囊 ‎開啟穿越澳洲之旅的那一刻展開了
‎…began when her family packed up their lives and traveled across Australia.
‎當她讀到獨立航海人杰西馬丁的書時
When she read solo sailor Jesse Martin's book,
‎便萌生了環球航海的念頭
she was inspired to circumnavigate the globe.
‎12歲的杰西卡 ‎一邊在家上學 一邊開始訓練
While homeschooled, 12-year-old Jessica began training
‎師從臭名昭著的水手本布萊恩特 ‎踏上了艱苦的逐夢之路
with infamous sailor Ben Bryant, and worked rigorously to pursue her dream.
‎但她的夢想是否演變成了噩夢
But has that dream turned into a nightmare?
‎劇情大反轉啊
Whoa! Plot twist!
‎兒童福利團體
Child welfare groups are calling
‎說這是不負責任和危險的嘗試
the attempt by the schoolgirl irresponsible and dangerous.
‎他們就愛多管閑事
They can't help themselves.
‎一個孩子沒有能力理解其中的風險
A child does not have the ability to understand the risks involved.
‎他們就沒其它 ‎更有意義的事可討論了嗎
You'd think they'd have something bloody better to talk about.
‎所有人都有一個疑問 ‎“杰西卡沃森是否太年輕了
The question on everyone's lips, "Is Jessica Watson too young,
‎以及 她的父母為何沒有加以制止 ”
and where are her parents in all of this?"
‎這令人不得不懷疑這究竟 ‎是杰西卡的夢想 還是她父母的
You do have to wonder if this is Jessica's dream or theirs.
‎社交媒體上也在議論 ‎他們說我們是“粗野的海盜”
It's on social media too. They're calling us "bogan pirates."
‎拜托 太好笑了
Oh, come on, that's great.
‎我要寫一個評論
Let me write a comment!
‎-不行 漢娜 ‎-不行
-No, Hannah. -No, Hanna, no.
‎昆士蘭政府正起草法案
The Queensland government is working on a bill
‎援引兒童福利政策 ‎意圖阻止杰西卡出海
to stop Jessica from sailing, citing child welfare.
‎他們不能這么做 他們可以嗎
They can't do that! Can they?
‎您所撥打的用戶無法接通 ‎請稍后再撥
The person you are calling is unavailable. Please try again.
‎應該沒那么糟吧
It can't be that bad.
‎沒那么糟 只是禍不單行而已
Oh, no. No, just everything's falling apart.
‎棚屋都訂滿了
Sheds are booked up.
‎我沒錢雇人幫忙 沒錢買零件 ‎贊助人也沒有任何回應
Can't afford help or parts, and now, none of my sponsors are responding.
‎你得給他們點兒時間
You have to give them a minute.
‎我沒時間了
I don't have time.
‎我猜他們一定在看新聞
I bet they're watching the news.
‎-所有人都說我做不到 ‎-誰在乎啊
-Everyone's saying I can't do it. -Who cares?
‎-你有信心就行 ‎-除非我能及時把小粉修好
-You think you can. -Only if I get Pink fixed in time.
‎我知道事情的進展不如預期
I know things aren't going according to plan,
這很令人沮喪
‎and… I know how frustrating that is.
‎但正是在出現差錯時 ‎你真實的品質才會展現出來
But it's when things go wrong that your true character's revealed.
‎現在在我眼前的 ‎是一個強大 堅定 頑強的姑娘
And right now, I'm looking at a strong, committed, tenacious young woman
‎她一定能解決面臨的問題
who will figure this out.
‎其余時候我都沒有這些品質嗎
So I'm not those things the rest of the time?
‎不 其余時候你就是個噩夢
No, the rest of the time you're an absolute nightmare.
‎是啊
Yeah.
‎只要你堅持不懈 ‎就能克服一切困難 杰絲
You can overcome anything if you keep working at it, Jess.
‎我已經見證過這一點了
I've watched you do it before.
‎（正如磁鐵的兩極一樣）
‎我做不到
It's impossible.
‎我們來試試你更感興趣的題材吧
Let's try something a little more up your alley.
‎色彩會幫你集中注意力 再試一次
The colors will help you focus. Try again.
‎杰西馬丁 最年輕的
"Jesse Martin, the youngest person
‎獨自航海
to s-- sail solo
‎環游世界的人
ar-- around the world."
‎環游整個世界
Around the whole world?
‎還能做這種事
You can do that?
‎我做了全面檢查 計算過成本
I did a full inspection and I got costs.
‎我們需要一根新桅桿 ‎還要更換索具 修補船體
And we'll need a new mast, new rigging, hull repairs.
‎應該只會稍微推遲一下
That is just a slight delay, I reckon.
‎只要我趕在11月之前出海就好
As long as I'm on the ocean before November.
‎-嘿 別神游了  ‎-什么
-Hello, Earth to Ben! -What?
‎拜托 我是認真的
Come on, Ben, I'm serious.
‎我們還能成行 來得及修好小粉…
We can still do this. -There's still time to fix up Pink--
‎我知道
‎-I know.
‎你要來嗎
-You coming?
‎去哪兒
Where to?
‎有東西給你看
Got something to show you.
‎-本 我不想要另一艘船 ‎-對
-Ben, I don't want another boat. -Yep.
‎我和小粉是一個團隊 我了解小粉
Pink and I are a team. I know Pink.
‎它鬧脾氣
I know when she's angry.
‎-或者出問題了 我都能知道 ‎-對
-I know when she's in trouble. -Yeah.
‎召集了一些幫手
Rounded up a bit of assistance.
‎自從媒體開始攻擊你
Once the media attacked you,
‎他們就自告奮勇來幫忙了 ‎我攔都攔不住
I couldn't stop 'em from volunteering to help.
‎為什么
Why?
‎因為媒體攻擊了我們自己人啊
Well, media went after one of our own.
‎雖然你要單獨出海 ‎但你現在也是有組織的人了
You might be sailing solo, but you belong to a tribe now.
‎我們趕在法案通過前 助你下水吧
This gets you on the water before they pass this blasted bill.
‎-你不是在做夢 杰絲 看看身后 ‎-她來啦
-It's all real, Jess. Look behind you. -She's here!
‎漢娜 什么也別碰 不行
Oi, Hannah, don't touch anything! No!
‎來吧
Come on!
‎布給我 謝了 伙計
Cloth? Thanks, mate.
‎好的 請稍等
Okay, just a sec.
‎對 是一 二 三 四
Right, it's one, two, three, four.
‎湯姆
Tom!
‎（我會一直想你哦 ‎艾米莉）
‎（廁所）
‎（敢于夢想）
‎嘿 羅杰 兄弟 有個小問題
Hey, Roger. -Rog, mate, just a quick question.
‎（粉紅號）
‎嘿 小粉
Hey, Pink.
‎歡迎回來
Welcome back.
‎-別鬧  ‎-淡定
-No! -Easy, easy!
‎他們就不能消停一天嗎
Can't they take a break for one day?
‎阻止杰西卡的呼聲越來越高
And calls to stop Jessica only grow.
‎就連她父親 ‎今日早些時候也表達了疑慮
Even her father expressed doubt earlier today.
‎羅杰 你對杰絲撞船一事感想如何
Rog! Man, how are you feeling about Jess's collision?
‎任何青少年出了這種事 ‎都會讓人擔心吧
Well, uh, you know, any teen crashing their vehicle doesn't exactly fill you with confidence, does it?
‎-說好的不回應媒體呢  ‎-我就是開個玩笑
What happened to not talking to the media? It was a joke.
‎-在國家電視臺上開的玩笑 ‎-他斷章取義了 知道嗎
That you made on national TV. Uh, he took it out of context, you know?
‎-你覺得我做不到嗎  ‎-什么
-Do you think I can't do it? -What?
我不知道
‎I don't know.
‎其實我之前以為 ‎你只是一時頭腦發熱 過一個月
To be honest, I thought this would be something you'd fixate on for a month
‎-就會拋諸腦后呢 ‎-別說了
and then you'd get over it. Rog, stop.
‎對不起
I'm sorry.
‎你不希望我去嗎
Do you wish I wasn't going?
‎嘿
Hey.
‎聽我說 好嗎
You listen to me, all right?
‎我希望你能實現所有的夢想
I want you to achieve everything that you aspire to.
‎但…
But…
‎你是我的寶貝女兒啊
you're my little girl.
‎對嗎
Yeah?
‎對
Yeah.
‎杰絲
Jess.
‎別吐槽我
Hey. Don't you start.
‎可惡
Damn it.
‎你知道他不是那個意思 ‎他只是害怕了
You know he doesn't mean it. He's just scared.
‎不 也許那些記者是對的
Maybe the journo's right, No.
‎也許我就該知難而退 ‎溜出去派對狂歡
maybe I should just… quit, and sneak out to parties.
‎相信我 ‎老爸絕對也不喜歡你干那種事
Dad definitely doesn't like that either. Trust me.
‎要知道 總會有人評頭論足
You know, people are always gonna have opinions
‎談論你該做什么 不該做什么的
on what you should and shouldn't be doing.
‎我見過你航海時有多開心
But I see how happy you are when you sail,
‎所以為了你自己 去吧
so just do it for you.
‎你真睿智
You're very wise.
‎好了 驚喜時間
All right. Surprise time.
‎好吧
-Okay.
‎我為你這趟旅程建了一個博客
I set up a blog for your trip.
‎-什么  ‎-別擔心 我會負責打理
-What? -Don't worry. I'll run it.
‎這樣每個人都能聽見你的聲音了
Then everyone can hear your voice,
‎我認為它有時候值得聆聽
'cause I think it's worth listening to. Sometimes.
‎謝謝你 艾米莉
Thanks, Em.
‎巧克力餅干
Tim Tam?
‎好的 我熱身完畢了
Okay, I'm warmed up.
‎-你們準備好了嗎 三 二 一 ‎-開拍
-You guys good? Three, two, one. -Rolling.
‎這一天終于來了
And the day has finally come.
‎再過幾個小時 幾經波折之后
In just a few hours and after several setbacks,
‎杰西卡沃森即將干勁十足地 ‎開啟她的獨自航海之旅
Jessica Watson is set to embark on her solo voyage,
‎不顧反對者們的聲音 ‎搶在政府法案頒布前出發
ignoring her critics and outrunning the government bill.
‎這個好 把這段加進新聞詞
Whoo! That's the one. Print that.
‎給 好的 謝了 親愛的
There you go. Yeah, thanks, darling.
‎孤單時就抱抱它吧
For when you get lonely.
‎我不能帶走科比考拉熊 ‎它是你的最愛
No, I can't take Kobi Koala. She's your favorite.
‎對
Yeah.
‎所以只是暫時借給你
That's why she's just on loan.
‎好嗎
Okay?
‎我保證一定把它安全帶回家
All right, then I promise to bring her home safe, yeah?
‎-好了 速戰速決吧 ‎-是啊
-All right, fast and quick. -Yeah.
‎為了擺脫家庭作業 ‎你也是豁出去了啊
Doing an awful lot to get out of homework.
‎再見 湯姆 好了
Bye, Tom. All right.
‎我打包了你要的巧克力 ‎別一口氣吃完
-So I packed the chocolate you asked for. -Don't eat it all in one go, all right?
‎謝謝你 爸爸
-Thanks, Dad.
‎每天給我打兩次電話 ‎匯報你所在的經緯度
I want you to call and give me your longs and lats twice a day.
‎為什么
Why?
‎如果報錯了 我就能知道你壓力很大
Because if you get them wrong, I'll know you're stressed.
‎利用閱讀障礙來監視我
Using dyslexia to spy on me?
‎沒錯 無論如何都不能漏打 好吧
Yeah, that's right. -No buts, all right?
‎你沒問題的
You'll be all right.
‎嘿
Hey.
‎要看日落 慶祝你的重大突破哦
celebrate the milestones, and… don't forget to dance in the rain.
‎還有 在雨中跳舞
Watch the sunsets,
‎一定要平安回來 好嗎
You come back home safe, okay?
‎你覺得它準備好了嗎
Do you think she's ready?
‎只有一個辦法能知道
Only one way to find out.
‎這是我首次航海時的護身符
It's a good luck charm from my first nav.
‎總能保我平安回來 現在歸你了
Always brought me back. It's yours now.
‎-本 我不能收 ‎-你能
-Ben, I can't. -'Course you can.
‎去吧 出海去吧
Go on. Get out of here.
‎-再見  ‎-再見 杰絲
Bye, Jess!
‎-再見 杰絲  ‎-再見 杰絲
‎祝你好運
Good luck!
‎再見
Bye!
‎她不會有事的
She'll be okay.
‎（粉紅女士）
‎（粉紅號）
‎好了
All right.
‎她到達起點了
There she is, starting now.
‎（官方出發線）
‎4點13分
-Four-point-one-three?
-Four-point-one-three.
‎（第一天 悉尼港 ‎2009年10月18日）
‎好啦 小粉
Oh, whoa! All right, Pink!
‎-你真惡心  ‎-我嘴里都塞滿了
-Ew, you're disgusting! -My mouth is full.
‎好了 大伙兒聽我說
Okay, so listen up.
‎本同意在這里追蹤杰絲的動向
Ben's agreed to work in here while, uh, he's tracking Jess,
‎給他騰個地方出來
so just give him a bit of space, all right?
‎做夢吧你…
In your dreams…
‎這是什么
What is all this stuff?
‎什么都別碰
Don't touch anything.
‎-那你也別碰我的麥片 ‎-行吧
-Then don't touch my Weet-Bix. -Fine.
‎行吧
-Fine.
‎好了
All right.
‎-是杰西卡的電話嗎  ‎-我來接
-Is that Jessica? -I got it! I got it.
‎我來 嘿 伙計
-Mine, mine, mine! Hey, mate.
‎南緯27度33分 東經170度30分
27 degrees, 33 minutes south, and 170 degrees, 30 minutes east.
‎正確
-Spot on.
‎-補給情況如何 充足嗎  ‎-爸 我這才剛出發
How are the supplies, do you have enough? Dad, I only just left.
別 朱莉…天吶…
‎Oh, no, Jules! Oh, my--
‎杰絲
Jess!
‎嗨 媽媽
Hi, Mum!
‎出海的感覺如何
How's it feel out there?
‎不枉我苦等這么久
Worth the wait.
‎把繩子拋過來
Chuck the rope.
‎交給我吧
I got it.
‎快扔呀
Just do it!
‎我技術可還行
Is that acceptable?
‎行 謝了 孩子
Yep. Thanks, kid.
‎他們都覺得我瘦弱 年紀小 ‎什么事都做不了
No one thinks I'm big or strong enough to do anything.
‎但我可以
But I am!
‎我一直在練習
I practice all the time, whenever I get the chance.
‎你不必向我證明任何事 伙計
You don't have to prove anything to me, mate.
‎但身為女孩子 我不得不證明自己
Well, that's what girls have to do.
‎你是本布萊恩特嗎
Are you Ben Bryant?
‎-不是 ‎-你是
-No. -Yes, you are.
‎你在南極洲航行時 ‎失去了小拇指的指尖
You lost the tip of your pinky finger sailing in Antarctica.
‎沒有失去
I didn't lose it.
‎-我把它放在抽屜里了 ‎-好吧
-I put it in the drawer. -Cool.
‎你12次從悉尼航行到霍巴特 ‎三次單人出海繞澳大利亞航行
You've done 12 Sydney to Hobarts and circumnavigated solo three times.
‎單人航海好玩嗎
Is solo sailing good?
‎是啊 可好玩了
Yeah, it's great.
‎沒人跟你說話
No one talks to you.
‎我想積累經驗 好出海環游世界
I'm trying to get experience so I can sail the world,
‎但沒人給我機會
but no one's giving me a chance to.
‎那就自己創造機會
So? Make your own chance.
‎嗨 我是杰絲
Hi, I'm Jess.
‎歡迎觀看我的視頻日志
Welcome to my video log!
‎傳統的做法是 水手們會寫日志
Traditionally, sailors keep log books,
‎但我可不要被剝奪半年的螢幕時間
but you can't deprive me of screen time for half a year.
‎不過 大概只有我媽會看這個吧
I'm sure it'll just be my mum watching, though.
‎嗨 媽媽
‎Hi, Mum!
‎我帶你參觀一下我未來七個月的家吧
I thought I'd give you a tour of my home for the next seven months,
‎那么…
so…
‎這是我的廚房 我會在這兒做飯
Here's my kitchen where I'll be cooking.
‎這是導航臺 ‎我在這里操控所有電器和通訊設備
And here is the nav table where I control all the electrics and communication.
‎我的床鋪 我在這兒睡覺
Uh, my berth, where I'll sleep.
‎廁所
Dunny.
‎這里是存放食物的地方
Uh, and this is where all my food is.
‎比如…
For example…
‎天吶 凍干西蘭花
Oh, my God, freeze-dried broccoli.
‎（巧克力 ‎吃過西蘭花才能吃 ）
‎干得漂亮 爸爸
Nice one, Dad.
‎我會獨自駕船連續行駛
So I'll be sailing unassisted and nonstop.
‎如果停靠港口 就會被取消資格
So if I pull into port, I'm disqualified.
‎我必須航行穿過所有經線 ‎繞過全部四個海岬
And I have to cross all lines of longitude and round all four capes
‎才能算真正完成了環球航海
for it to count as a true circumnavigation.
‎這是我的預計航線
Here's what I'll be doing.
‎這里是悉尼
Okay, here's Sydney.
‎往東北走 越過赤道
Going northeast, up past the equator,
‎然后南下 繞過智利南端的合恩角
then back down south to round Cape Horn at the tip of Chile,
‎繼而橫渡大西洋 前往南非的好望角
then across the Atlantic Ocean to the Cape of Good Hope in South Africa,
‎接著穿過印度洋 ‎到澳洲西部的露紋角
then over the Indian Ocean to Cape Leeuwin in Western Australia,
‎繼續行至塔斯馬尼亞島的東南角
then down around the South East Cape in Tasmania,
‎最后回到悉尼港
and back up to Sydney Harbor.
‎所以 其實不算太難啦
So not so much really.
‎跟我來
Come on!
‎好了 這是開船用的舵柄
All right, so this is the tiller to steer,
‎但目前處于自動駕駛模式
but it's on autopilot at the moment.
‎這下面是救生艇
Uh, the lifeboat is under here,
‎這里面是浮錨
and in here is the drogue.
‎它類似于船錨 不過是軟的
It's like a soft anchor.
‎它能讓船在風暴中減速和保持穩定
It slows the boat down during storms and keeps it stable.
‎這是我的淋浴用品
Here's my shower,
‎但我好像把梳子落家里了
although I have discovered that I left my hairbrush at home.
‎所以接下來的200天 只好用這個代替
So I'll just have to use this for 200 days.
‎至少后院的景致值回票價了
At least the backyard makes up for it, though.
‎餓了嗎 科比
Hungry, Kobi?
‎-杰絲 ‎-嘿
-Jess. -Hey.
‎船舶偵測警報運作正常 ‎有一艘船剛從我的西北邊駛過
Uh, ship detection alarms work. Uh, one just went past northwest of me.
‎好的 在這之后的很長一段時間 ‎你都不會再看到其他船只
Good to know. Well, that'll be the last ship you see for a while now.
‎你怎么知道
How do you know?
‎聽著 你要從那次撞船中 ‎吸取教訓 好嗎
Listen, let that crash be a lesson to you, eh?
‎你現在知道該怎么處理了
You know how to handle it now.
‎-你會覺得孤單嗎  ‎-有時候會
-Did you ever get lonely? -Oh, sometimes.
‎-但我知道該怎么克服 ‎-怎么克服
-But I know how to get over it. -How?
‎唱歌
-Sing.
‎唱歌 你會唱歌
-Sing? You-- You sang?
‎我們是水手 當然要唱歌
We're sailors. That's what we're supposed to do.
‎去睡會兒吧 好嗎
Try to get some sleep, eh?
‎你只是在航程第一周有點緊張罷了 ‎喔 有魚上鉤了
You've just got the first-week jitters, that's all. Oh! Fish are calling.
‎-我得先掛了 ‎-好
-Gotta go. -Okay.
‎來吧
Come on.
‎可惡
Oh, bugger!
‎（第12天 太平洋水域 臨近斐濟）
‎…本地女孩引起全國關注
…the local girl who is now attracting national attention.
‎杰西卡沃森一家 ‎曾駕駛特制的雙層巴士周游澳洲
Jessica Watson's family traveled Australia in a purpose-built double-decker bus
‎后來在杰西卡九歲時 ‎搬到了船上居住
before moving onto a boat when Jessica was nine.
‎如今 七年后 杰西卡即將跨越 ‎人生中的第一個重要里程碑
the first major milestone in her attempt to be the youngest person… Now, seven years later, Jessica is about to cross
‎挑戰單人環球航海 ‎成為完成此舉的最年輕人士
…to sail solo around the world. There we go.
‎謝謝你 蘇西 ‎真正的危險在印度洋和南冰洋海域
Thanks, Susie. The real danger, of course, will be the Indian and Southern Oceans, where dozens of sailors,
‎在那里 數十位比杰西卡沃森 ‎更為經驗豐富的水手
who are far more experienced than young Jessica Watson,
‎都曾接二連三地經歷了翻船
have endured knockdown after knockdown.
‎沒必要給我們聽這個
Didn't need to hear that.
‎嘗試環球航行的獨自航海人 ‎要忍受數月的…
-Solo sailors looking to circumnavigate the globe endure many months…
‎穿越赤道對水手來說是一件大事
Okay, so crossing the equator is a big deal for sailors.
‎你由此證明自己的航海實力
You've proven your seaworthiness and must be initiated
‎被正式接納為水手團體的一員
into the Fraternity of Mariners.
‎好的 那么…
Okay, so…
‎赤道以南 20米 15米 ‎十 五 零
South, twenty, fifteen, ten, five, zero!
‎我們從南半球進入北半球啦
We crossed from the Southern Hemisphere into the Northern Hemisphere!
‎好的 作為我的入團儀式…
Okay, for the initiation ceremony…
‎好清爽啊
Quite refreshing, actually.
‎敬海神
A toast to King Neptune!
‎（第33天 赤道 離家7010公里）
‎-敬杰西 ‎-杰西 干杯
-To Jess. -To Jess! Cheers!
‎真不敢相信 ‎她已經穿越了赤道 太酷了
I can't believe she's crossed the equator. So cool.
‎（澳洲 ‎北美洲-南美洲）
‎紅色晚霞 水手歡喜 ‎紅色朝霞 水手警醒
Red sky at night, sailor's delight. Red sky in the morning, sailor's warning.
‎看天氣預報了嗎
See the forecast?
‎嗯 天象已經說明了一切
Yeah, sky says it all.
‎對 杰絲 這會是一場大風暴 ‎我們來商量對策吧
Yeah. Jess, this is gonna be a big one. Let's talk game, eh?
‎我會改變航向
I'll change course.
‎我的建議是拋出浮錨 抗過去
I think you should launch the drogue. Weather it.
‎穿過風暴
Go through the storm?
‎風暴的移動速度很快 ‎你不可能繞過去的
Well, it's moving fast. There's no way you're gonna outrun it.
‎-但只要抗住 它很快就過去了 ‎-謝天謝地
But that also means it's gonna pass quickly. -Thank God.
‎慢著 我們說好了安全至上的
-W-- Hang on, hang on. We agreed to do whatever's safest.
‎風暴在這個區域并不常見 ‎爸爸 很難判斷的
Storms in this region aren't common, Dad. It's hard to judge.
‎浮錨就像船錨一樣
It's like an anchor.
‎會幫助她保持穩定 她不會有事的
The drogue will keep her stable. She'll be okay.
‎我認為這是最好的選擇 ‎杰絲 你決定吧
I think it's our best option, Jess. It's your call.
‎好吧
Okay.
‎跟我說說
-Talk to me.
‎操作流程 對 我們分解研究一下
Protocols. Yeah, let's break it down.
‎我不知道 我不喜歡這計劃
I don't know. I don't-- I don't like this.
‎不管你怎么想 本是專業的 杰絲也是
Ben knows his stuff, whatever you think of him. What's more, so does Jess.
‎你知道該怎么做
-You know the drill.
‎對
-Yeah.
‎來吧 浮錨
Come on, drogue!
‎我有話跟你們說 ‎我想獨自駕船環球航行
I have something to tell you. I want to circumnavigate the world solo.
‎并打破達成這一成就的最小年齡紀錄
And I'm gonna be the youngest person to do it.
杰絲…
Uh, Jess…
‎什么
What?
‎杰西馬丁17歲就做到了 ‎他是個跟我一樣的普通小孩
Jesse Martin did it when he was 17. He was an ordinary kid, so am I.
‎我已經計劃好了
Don't worry, I've got a plan.
‎我要找個老師 拿到資格證
I'll get a teacher, qualifications.
‎這上面列出了所有我需要做的事 ‎還有一開始要上的安全課
Here's a list of all the things I'll need and the safety courses I'll do to start.
‎我會通過打工掙錢和拉贊助 ‎來支付重大開銷
I'll get jobs to earn money, and find sponsors to cover the big costs,
‎每航海一個小時 ‎我都會相應地做一小時閱讀
and for every hour I sail, I'll still do an hour of reading.
‎那閱讀量可不小呢
-Now, that's a good amount of reading!
‎-她很了解自己的聽眾 ‎-是啊
-She knows her audience. -Yeah.
‎那你就開始實施這些計劃吧
Well, uh, you'd better start working through that list, then. Thoroughly.
‎只要你下定決心的事 一定能辦到
I think you can do anything you set your mind to, honey.
‎杰絲 你沒事吧
-Jess! You okay?
‎-我沒事 ‎-出什么事了 你怎么沒來電話
-Yeah, I'm fine. -What happened? Why didn't you call?
‎我被東西砸暈了 但我沒事
Well, I got knocked out, but I'm fine.
‎-什么  ‎-砸暈了 你還好嗎
-What? -Knocked out? Are you okay?
‎-有腦震蕩嗎  ‎-帥啊
-Do you have a concussion? -Sick.
‎-你需要醫生  ‎-船上沒有
-You need a doctor! -Oh, I didn't pack one of those.
‎杰絲 聽完說
Hey, come on. Jess, listen to me.
‎你覺得頭痛 耳鳴 惡心嗎
Do you have a headache, ringing in the ears, or nausea or something?
‎爸爸 別大驚小怪了 我沒事
Dad, please stop. I'm fine.
‎本在嗎
Is Ben there?
‎小粉怎么樣
How's Pink?
‎它沒事
Yeah, she's all right.
‎你沒系好安全帶嗎
You weren't strapped in, were you?
‎-我當時正準備系呢 ‎-你應該更早系好
-I was getting there. -Well, you should've already been there.
‎大自然從來不等人 你知道的
Mother Nature doesn't wait for anyone. You know that, Jess.
‎-那可是風暴啊 ‎-不管是什么
It was a storm. It doesn't matter.
‎你都得處理好 ‎這次能平安度過是你運氣好
You have to manage it. You're just lucky you got through this one.
‎真是太瘋狂了 ‎我原本還打算繞過去的
It was so wild, Ben. I thought we were gonna go all the way around.
‎是啊
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
‎（第50天 南美洲近海岸）
‎本出來了 快來
Oh, it's Ben. Let's go.
‎我們聽說杰絲經歷了第一場風暴 ‎有任何損傷嗎
Ben! We just had word Jess went through her first storm. Any injuries or damage?
‎我們不會回答任何問題 ‎但杰絲建了一個博客 這是地址
We aren't taking any questions, but Jess has a blog at this address.
‎轉移視線的基本法
Diversion 101.
‎其實也沒那么難呀 本
It's not that hard, Ben.
‎-本 你有什么要補充的嗎  ‎-本 不好意思 就一會兒
Is there anything you can add? Ben, excuse me. Excuse me! Just one sec. She's going through--
‎-等一下 本 抱歉 ‎-吉米 幫我拿一下
-Wait! Wait, Ben, sorry. -Jimmy, hold this.
‎在大海中央航行 ‎信天翁是唯一可見的生物
An albatross, one of the only living things you see in the middle of the ocean.
‎它們一直以來都是水手們觀察的目標
They've been watched by sailors throughout history.
‎我好像釣到魚啦
I think I caught a fish!
‎好的
Okay.
‎好嘞
Ooh! Okay.
‎過來 能看見嗎
Come over here! Can you see it?
‎你好呀
Oh! Hello.
‎該我了
-My turn!
‎好了 湯姆 早餐好了
All right! Tom, grub's up!
‎-好的 ‎-來了
-Yup. -Here you go.
‎吃吧
-Eat up! -Thank you.
‎早上好
Morning!
‎本 這是你的
Ben? Here you go.
‎我不吃早餐
I don't eat breakfast.
‎不吃就不吃吧 ‎但你想吃的話 隨時可以
Uh, well, don't then, but it's here if you want it.
‎想寫點什么嗎
Want to write something?
‎（湯姆國王）
‎杰絲 我被悉尼大學錄取啦
Jess, I got into Sydney Uni!
‎天吶 艾米莉 太棒了  ‎恭喜呀 你成功啦
Oh, my gosh! Em, that's fantastic! Congratulations, you did it!
‎漢娜已經在預謀霸占我的床了
I should warn you, Hannah's already gunning for my bed.
‎對哦
Right.
‎等我回去你都走了
Oh, you'll be gone before I get back.
‎但我還是會幫你打理博客的
Yeah, I'll still run the blog, though.
‎我在游泳嘉年華上贏了四枚獎牌哦
Jess, I won four medals at the swimming carnival!
‎漢娜 太棒啦 真希望我能親眼看到
Wow, Han! That's amazing! I wish I could have been there.
‎知道嗎 湯姆交女朋友了
And guess what? Tom has a date.
‎-你干嗎… ‎-什么 誰呀
-Why would you-- -What? With who?
‎給我…
-Give me the… Okay.
‎杰絲
-Jess! -I want the phone!
‎-我沒有 我不知道她在說什么… ‎-他有
I don't, I don't! -I don't know what-- -Yes, he does!
‎他有
-I'm telling her! -He does! He does!
‎讓我跟她說 我來告訴她是誰
I'm talking to her and I'm telling her who it is!
‎我沒有女朋友
I don't have-- I don't have a date.
‎-他有  ‎-我沒有女朋友
-He does! -I don't have a date.
‎我贏了
Snap.
‎-繼續 你收到了什么  ‎-沖浪板
-Go on, what do you got? -Boogie board!
‎什么 沖浪板
-What? A boogie board?
‎漢娜吃糖吃瘋了
You'll be shocked to hear that Hannah's riled up on sugar.
‎我也是 這都還沒到圣誕節呢
Well, she's not the only one. And it's not even Christmas here yet.
‎-艾米莉在嗎  ‎-在 等一下
-Oh, is Em around? -Yeah, hold on!
‎艾米莉
Em.
‎嘿 杰絲 圣誕快樂
Hey, Jess. Merry Christmas!
‎圣誕快樂
Merry Christmas!
‎一包友情種子
A Grow Your Own Friend!
‎謝謝 太合我心意啦
Aw, thank you, Em, it's just what I need.
‎我聽說植物是很棒的傾聽者
-Yeah, I hear she's a great listener.
‎-該我了  ‎-爸要跟你說
-Hey, my turn! -Oh, here's Dad.
‎圣誕快樂 親愛的 聽說你有新朋友了
Merry Christmas, love. Hey, I hear you've got a new mate.
‎你們明天有什么安排
What have you two got planned for tomorrow then?
‎我會主辦派對 ‎但我的客人們要比你那邊安靜多了
Oh, well, I'm hosting, uh, but my guests are a little quieter than yours.
‎好酷呀 漢娜
-That's pretty cool, Hannah.
‎聽起來真不錯 我能到你那邊去嗎
That sounds great! Mind if I come to yours?
‎杰絲 我忘說了 去找裝大蔥的袋子
Jess! I forgot. Find the leeks bag.
‎你聽見了嗎 裝大蔥的袋子
Do you hear that? Leeks bag.
‎本
Ben!
‎-圣誕快樂  ‎-對
Merry Christmas! Yeah.
‎進來吧
Come on in.
‎圣誕快樂 本
Merry Christmas, Ben!
‎-圣誕快樂 本  ‎-好
-Merry Christmas, Ben! -Yeah.
‎圣誕快樂 伙計
Merry Christmas, mate.
‎-給 ‎-謝謝
-There you are. -Oh, thanks.
‎我很喜歡 謝啦 湯姆
Oh, I love them. Thank you, Tom.
‎好了 你們那邊有點吵 我先掛了哦
All right, it's a bit loud. I'm gonna go now.
‎大家說再見
Everybody say goodbye to Jess!
‎-我們愛你  ‎-好的 回聊 杰絲
-We love you! -Yeah, see you, Jess!
‎湯姆 音樂
Tom, music!
‎好
Yup.
‎-拿著 ‎-好啊 干杯
-Take this. -Yeah. Cheers.
‎是啊 你就像…
Yeah, you're like…
‎好了 飯菜上桌嘍 來吃吧
All right, food's on the table! Come on, you lot.
‎大伙兒都餓了吧
Hope you're hungry!
‎好了 拉炮時間 漢娜 來 用力拉
Right, cracker time, Han, come on. Big pull!
‎抱歉 本
-Sorry, Ben. -Ben.
‎本 你往常都怎么過圣誕節呀
Ben, what do you usually do for Christmas?
‎不過
Nothing.
‎你的家人呢
What about your family?
‎沒有家人
Oh. Uh, don't have one.
‎-圣誕快樂 ‎-給我的
-Merry Christmas. -For me?
‎打開看看
Open it, open it!
‎謝謝
Thank you.
‎本 為什么合恩角那么重要
Ben, why is Cape Horn such a big deal?
‎這個嘛…
Oh! Well…
‎它可是非常考驗航海技術的
That is some wicked sailing.
‎那里是大西洋和太平洋的交匯處
See, that's where the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans meet,
‎有狂風呼嘯 洋流翻騰
so you get these powerful winds, these churning currents,
‎還有兩大洋相互碰撞時 ‎掀起的滔天的巨浪
these humongous waves as the oceans smash together.
‎正因如此 那段航道兇險萬分
That's why that passage is so sinister.
‎海里飄滿了前輩水手們的…手指尖
It's absolutely littered with a long-lost trail of fingertips.
‎本 你在說到我們女兒身處險境時 ‎能別這么興奮嗎
-Uh, Ben? Uh, could you maybe be a little less excited about our daughter doing something sinister?
‎好吧
All right.
‎你是指船會開得很快嗎
We talking fast sailing?
‎快得不得了
-Wicked fast.
‎天啊
-Oh, my.
‎（第82天 合恩角 離家17420公里）
‎瞧她現在船速多快啊 天吶
Look how fast she's going. Bloody hell.
-別開太快呀 ‎-她開得好快
Oh, not-- not too fast. It's… -She's going quick.
‎加油啊
Come on!
‎我們剛剛繞過了 ‎航海界的珠峰 合恩角
We just rounded the Everest of the ocean, Cape Horn,
‎我很高興地宣布 這次航行很順利
and I am happy to report it was smooth sailing.
‎而且很酷
And so cool!
‎我真不敢相信
I, uh-- I just-- I just can't believe it.
‎我們通過了最大的挑戰
It's like we've passed our biggest challenge.
‎（南美洲-非洲）
‎（第113天 沒有風的第一天 ‎離家20735公里）
‎你聽見了嗎
Do you hear that?
‎一點聲音也沒有
It's the sound of nothing.
‎萬籟俱寂
Nothing at all.
‎沒有風 沒有海浪
There's no wind or waves.
‎已經好幾天了
It's been days.
‎你知道我在哪里
You know where I am.
‎我要環球航海 ‎現在聘請你當我的教練
I'm gonna sail around the world and I'm hiring you as my coach.
‎告訴你爸媽 航海學校有一大堆教練
Tell your parents there's plenty of coaches at the sailing school.
‎-我知道 但我想跟你學 ‎-可是…
Well… I know, but I want you to do it.
‎我已經不再航海了
I don't sail anymore.
‎因為千禧杯的事 我知道
Because of the Millennium Cup, I know.
‎但如果你的學生 ‎成為了歷史上最年輕的
But if you help the youngest person in history
‎獨自完成環球航海的人
sail solo around the world,
‎人們就不會揪著馬特特納的事不放了
people will let go of what happened with Matt Turner.
‎他們也許會放下 但我不會
They might, but I won't.
‎話說回來 你為什么想干這個
Hey, why-- why do you want to do this, anyway?
‎因為這年頭沒有人再去探險了
‎'Cause… no one explores anymore.
‎登上太空的人比環球航海的人還多
You know, there have been more people in space than have sailed around the world.
‎我之前甚至不知道有環球航海這回事 ‎但它確實存在 而我想去做
I didn't even know it was something you can do, but you can, and I want to.
‎因為我是個探險家
'Cause I'm an adventurer.
‎你喜歡航海
You like sailing.
‎但環球航行完全是另一回事
Circumnavigating the globe is a whole different thing, mate.
‎我想自己去尋找答案
Well, that's what I want to find out for myself.
‎無論我說什么 ‎都無法動搖你的決心 對嗎
You're gonna do this no matter what I say, aren't you?
‎如果我答應了 ‎我可是不會給你特別待遇的
If I was going to agree to this, I'm not gonna treat you special,
‎因為大海對所有人一視同仁
'cause it doesn't matter out there.
‎我只會像對待自己一樣嚴格要求你
I'll only treat you how I treat myself.
第一條規則 別抱我
First rule… don't do that.
‎嚇死我了
It freaks me out.
‎（第115天 無風的第三天）
‎（保持堅強 爸爸）
‎-就是這樣 來吧 ‎-好
-That's it. Come on. -Okay.
‎本 你都好幾天沒睡了 休息一下吧
-Ben, you've barely slept in days, mate. -Take a break.
‎什么 不用 我沒事
-Oh, nah. No, no. I'm good.
‎只是在等日志更新
Just, um, waiting on these logs.
‎杰絲在干什么
What is Jess doing?
‎（第117天 無風的第五天）
‎杰絲
Jess?
‎你已經反方向行駛幾個小時了
You've been going backwards for hours, mate.
‎對 我之前睡著了
Yeah, I was asleep.
‎你沒設置警報嗎
So you didn't set the alarms?
‎一周都沒怎么挪動 ‎我怎么知道船會倒著走
Well, barely moved in a week, how would I know we're going backwards?
‎所以才要設置警報啊
Again, that's why you set the alarms, mate!
‎對 好吧 冷靜點
Yeah, okay, chill out.
‎“冷靜” 這樣很危險 好吧
"Chill out"? Hey, this is dangerous, okay?
‎就是這種時候會出差錯 會有人受傷
This is when things go wrong, when people get hurt,
‎因為某些人的玩忽職守
when people neglect their responsibilities!
‎再這樣下去 你會害死自己的
And you, if you keep on like this, you're gonna get yourself killed!
‎是嗎 這種事你最清楚了
Yeah? Well, you'd know!
‎喂 什么情況
Oi! What's going on?
‎我…
I, uh…
‎你說得對 杰絲
You're right, Jess.
‎對
Yeah.
‎我需要冷靜一下
I need to chill out.
‎杰絲
Jess?
‎這里沒有風 沒有浪
There's no wind, and there's no waves,
‎現在連本也不理我了
and now there's no Ben.
‎只剩我一個人
And it's just me.
‎而我無法擺脫我自己
And I-- I can't get away from myself.
‎（第119天 無風的第七天）
‎我還是停在原地
I still haven't moved.
‎謝天謝地 你終于接電話了  ‎出什么事了 杰絲
Oh, thank God you picked up! What's going on, Jess?
‎媽媽
Mum.
‎怎么啦
What is it?
‎沒事了 我在呢
It's okay. I'm here.
‎說吧
Get it out.
‎我太孤單了
I'm so alone.
‎不 你不是一個人
No, you're not.
‎我知道孤單的感覺有多可怕
I know how awful it is to feel like this.
‎但不會一直這樣下去的
But… it won't last forever.
‎我沒法告訴你何時會起風
I can't tell you when the wind will pick up,
但我知道只要你堅持下去
‎but… I know that if you keep going,
‎風一定會來的
it will.
‎就像你的每一位
Just as it has done
‎水手前輩都經歷過的那樣
for every sailor before you.
‎還記得我以前常給你唱的那首歌嗎
Do you remember the song I used to sing to you at night?
‎嗯
Yeah.
‎我要你去找夜空中最明亮的那顆星
I want you to search for the brightest star in the sky.
‎每當你凝望它的時候
And every time you look at it,
‎要知道遠在家中的我…
at home… know that I'm here,
‎也凝望著同一顆星辰
staring at that same star.
‎我與你同在
I'm with you.
‎知道嗎
Okay?
‎嗯 好
Yeah, okay.
‎我愛你 杰絲
I love you, Jess.
‎我也愛你
I love you too.
‎有一個外星人在天上等待
‎他想過來見我們
‎但害怕嚇到我們
‎有一個外星人在天上等待
‎嗨
Hi.
‎抱歉 我最近沒怎么錄視頻
Sorry I haven't been here much.
‎我在逃避
I've been avoiding a lot.
‎老實說 實現夢想的過程很艱難
Mmm, the truth is that living your dream is hard.
‎而現在異常艱辛
And right now it's really hard.
‎我哭了好幾個小時
I've been crying for hours.
‎我很疲憊
I'm tired.
‎我全身酸痛
I'm sore.
‎連腿都伸展不開
I can't properly stretch my legs.
‎我想念我的家人
I miss my family.
‎很想很想
I miss them a lot.
‎我也想我那個愛發脾氣的顧問…
And I miss my grouchy advisor…
‎他也是我最好的朋友
…who's also my best friend.
‎一直以來
Ah, but through it all,
‎我都在努力做一個堅韌不拔的探險家
I've tried to be this-- this tough, stoic explorer.
‎但那不是真的我 知道嗎
And… that's not me, you know?
‎我并不總是樂觀向上 ‎內心強大 無所畏懼的
I'm not always fine, or strong, or fearless.
‎無所畏懼…我經常會害怕
Phew! "Fearless." I'm often terrified!
‎會懷疑自己
And I doubt myself.
‎而且…
And…
‎經常會想要放棄
I think a lot about giving up.
‎但沒關系
But that's okay.
‎沒關系的
It's okay.
‎因為堅持做自己 ‎這件事本身會給人力量
'Cause there's-- there's strength in being yourself.
‎我覺得
You know, I think…
‎這就像攀登山峰一樣艱難
that's as hard as climbing any mountain.
‎承認自己的脆弱
You know, I think there's bravery
‎需要極大的勇氣
in admitting that you're not okay.
‎天吶 這真的很嚇人
Oh, God, it's scary.
‎就像在風暴中被掀翻下船一樣可怕
It's as scary as… almost being swept overboard in the middle of a storm.
‎并不是說我有掉下船過哦 爸媽
Not that I'd know, Mum and Dad.
‎我是杰西卡沃森
So… I'm Jessica Watson.
‎對 我很堅強 我正在掙扎
Yeah, I'm tough and I'm struggling.
‎實現夢想的過程雖然艱辛
And living my dream is-- is-- is hard,
‎但我甘之如飴
but it's so worth it.
‎哪怕在最難熬的日子里
-Even the bad days.
‎因為這個世界…
Because the world…
‎對 有時候它荊棘密布
Yeah, it can be a difficult place, but it's…
‎但同時 它也美如仙境
…it's also really, really beautiful.
‎小粉 你找到風啦
Pink, you found the wind!
‎（北美洲-南美洲 ‎非洲）
‎（非洲-澳洲）
‎（鮑伊號）
‎（澳洲）
‎你好
G'day!
‎（澳洲少女挑戰單人航海世界紀錄）
‎幫個忙好嗎 可回收垃圾扔那邊 ‎今天是垃圾收集日
Do you mind? Recycling's over there. It's bin day.
‎（踏上歸途）
‎（喲：水手沃森穿越露紋角）
‎（杰西卡沃森穿越露紋角）
‎（第186天 南冰洋 ‎離家4892公里）
‎杰絲
-Jessy!
‎嗨 爸爸 本有話說嗎
Hi, Dad. Um, any word from Ben?
‎他在他的船上追蹤你
He's tracking you from his boat.
‎他沒事
He's okay.
‎他只是需要點時間
He just needs a minute, love.
‎這要不是無間斷航海
If this weren't nonstop,
‎我和小粉一定會入港維修 毫無疑問
we would be pulling into port for repairs, no question.
‎船漏水這情況可不是喜聞樂見的
I mean, leaking on a boat is not what you want.
‎但只要視野清晰海況好
But as long as we've got a clear shot and an easy run back home,
‎小粉應該能堅持住
it should hold.
‎小粉的設計是 ‎哪怕翻倒過去也能自行回正的
Pink's designed to correct herself if we roll over,
‎只要在沒有漏水的情況下
as long as there are no leaks.
‎本應該也會這么說
That's what Ben would say too, I reckon.
‎今天有很多離岸流 ‎知道該怎么做嗎
A lot of rips out there today. Know what you're doing?
‎順應水勢
-Go with 'em.
‎不要與之對抗
‎-Don't fight it.
‎大海永遠比你 ‎比任何其他生物都要強大
The ocean'll always be stronger than you and every other being.
‎若你想航海 ‎最好學會與大自然和諧相處
If you wanna sail, better learn to get along with Mother Nature.
‎它沒有絲毫惡意
She doesn't mean you any harm,
‎只是在做它該做的事情 ‎但有時候人類擅自闖入了
she's just doing her thing and sometimes we get in the way.
‎來吧
Come on then.
‎我們下海
Let's get in there.
‎（澳洲）
‎（第197天 南冰洋 ‎離家2556公里）
‎杰西卡 我是澳大利亞總理
Jessica, this is the Prime Minister of Australia.
‎你也可以叫我陸克文…
-You can call me K-Rudd if you-- -Gimme this.
‎嘿 湯姆 怎么啦
Hey, Tom. What's up?
‎總理一直提起你
To be fair, the prime minister has been talking about you.
‎艾米莉 你回家啦
Em, you're home!
‎就待一周
Just for the week.
‎我學校的人都知道你是誰了
It's crazy, everyone at uni knows who you are.
‎我可不想當名人
-Oh, God. I don't know if I want that. -Well, then brace yourself.
‎你繞過露紋角的照片 ‎登上了世界各地的報紙
That picture of you rounding the cape is in newspapers all over the world.
‎大家都在為你喝彩
Everyone's cheering for you.
‎拜托 打理一下你的頭發吧
So please start doing your hair.
‎拜托 我只能用叉子梳頭
Oh, come on. I have a fork for a brush.
‎大學怎么樣  ‎有在悉尼認識新的男生嗎
How's uni? Any new boys in Sydney?
‎也許吧
Maybe!
‎天吶 誰呀
Oh, my God, who?
‎這個嘛…
Well…
‎嘿 你能讓媽媽接一下電話嗎
Hey, uh, could you get Mum on the phone?
‎馬上
Now?
‎前方有惡劣天氣 非常惡劣 是風暴群
Bad weather on the way. Really bad. Storms.
‎風暴 而且不止一個
"Storms," plural?
‎是來自南極洲的氣旋 ‎規模是上次那場風暴的五倍
They're even coming right at me from Antarctica. Five times the size of the last storm.
‎我想你可能得入港了
I think you might have to pull into port.
‎放棄嗎 不行 做不到 ‎我不能現在放棄
Quit? No. No, I can't. Not now.
‎-我認為你別無選擇 ‎-讓我看看天象
I'm not sure you're gonna have an option here. Let me check the sky.
‎你為什么要這么對我  ‎就不能放我一馬嗎
Why-- Why are you doing this to me? Why couldn't you just give me a break?
‎風暴前緣已經帶來了
The front's already generating gale force winds
‎130公里每小時的強風 ‎伴隨12米高的巨浪
of 70 knots, with a 40-foot swell.
‎杰西卡沃森會駛入港口 被取消資格
So will Jessica pull into port but get disqualified in the process,
‎還是會繼續前進
or keep going?
‎謝謝你 克雷格 ‎如果她選擇穿過巴斯海峽呢
Thanks, Craig. What about cutting through Bass Straight?
‎她能借此抵擋惡劣天氣
It's an option, and could shield her from the worst of the weather.
‎-以錯過第四個海岬為代價 ‎-但她能保住命 蘇西
Though she'd miss the fourth cape. But she'll live, Susie.
‎這是我們現在討論的重點 她的生存
That's what we're talking about here, isn't it? Her survival.
‎澳大利亞青年水手 ‎杰西卡沃森的環球航海嘗試
Australian teen sailor Jessica Watson has been confronted by another challenge in her attempt to become the youngest person
‎再次面臨挑戰
to circumnavigate the world.
‎你不用覺得羞恥
You have nothing to be ashamed of.
‎哪怕最經驗老道的水手都會選擇靠岸
Even the most experienced sailors would pull in too.
‎就連本也會
Yeah, even Ben would.
‎朱莉
Jules.
‎我會讓所有人失望的
Yeah, but I'm gonna let everyone down.
‎不會有人失望的 ‎你沒看那些評論嗎
You're not letting anyone down. -Have you even seen your comments?
‎什么評論
What comments?
‎你博客上的評論
On your blog.
‎-我教過你怎么看評論的 ‎-你沒有
-Told you how to do this. No, you didn't.
‎我有
Yes, I did.
‎好吧 打開筆記本電腦
Okay, open your laptop.
‎點擊任何一篇博文的鏈接
Click the link on to any post.
‎鼠標往下滾動 然后看吧
Scroll down and watch.
‎我每天早上都會查看你的最新動態
I can't wait to check how you're doing every morning.
‎你比我認識的所有人都堅強
You're stronger than anyone I know.
‎公有住房區有14個孩子
There are 14 children on the council estate
‎借了我的電腦去追你的視頻日志
who borrow my computer to follow your video diary.
‎你給了這些孩子很大的鼓舞
Oh, you are such an inspiration to these kids.
‎我要攀登七大高峰
I am going to climb the Seven Summits.
‎謝謝你讓我看見了 ‎這并非遙不可及的夢
Thank you for making me see it doesn't have to just be a dream.
‎我今年12歲 也患有閱讀障礙
I'm 12 years old and I'm also dyslexic.
‎追你的視頻讓我開始覺得
Following your videos has made me think
‎我也能去追逐夢想 ‎有朝一日成為飛行員
that I can also reach my dream and one day become a pilot.
‎謝謝你帶我們一起 ‎走上這段旅程 沃森船長
Thanks for making us part of your journey, Captain Watson.
‎我回頭再打給你
I'm gonna call you back.
‎我們眼看就要成功了
We are so close.
‎那么…
So, so…
‎一 二 三
One, two, three.
‎我們愛你 杰西卡
We love you, Jessica!
‎悉尼見
See you in Sydney!
‎一定有辦法的
There has to be a way.
‎我只想帶她回家
I just want to get her home.
‎好的 我反復計算過數據 ‎還有一個選擇
Okay, so I've done the numbers over and over, and there is another option.
‎我可以跑贏風暴
I could outrun the western storm.
‎-不 絕對不行 ‎-本 你回來了
-No, not gonna happen. -Ben, you're back?
‎對 杰絲 之前是我不好 ‎我不該發火的
Yeah. About that, Jess, I shouldn't have lost it.
‎我讓恐懼戰勝了理智 對不起
I let fear take over, and I'm sorry.
‎不 該說對不起的是我
No. No, no, no, I'm sorry.
‎聽著 我…
-Look, I--
‎我當時想說的是 ‎“我不是他 這也不是千禧杯”
What I meant was that I'm not him and this isn't the Millennium Cup,
‎你不會失去我的 你休想擺脫我
and you're not gonna lose me, Ben. You're stuck with me.
‎風暴要來了 記得嗎
Uh, storm incoming, remember?
‎對 最猛烈的風暴會在72小時后抵達
Yeah. So the worst of the storms are gonna hit in 72 hours,
‎如果我能穿過去呢
so what if I go through them?
‎這不是你能硬抗的風暴
What? These are not the kind of storms you weather.
‎我沒想硬抗 我想不用浮錨 順應風勢
No, I don't want to weather them, I want to move with them by not using the drogue.
‎杰絲 浮錨是用來 ‎保持船身穩定的 不能不用
Jess, you have to. The drogue's what keeps the boat stable.
‎對 但在太平洋風暴群里 ‎浮錨會拖慢我的速度
Yeah, but in the Pacific storms, it slowed us down like an anchor.
‎對 要的就是慢
Yeah, that's the point!
‎但小粉在上次對抗風暴時 ‎就被海浪沖擊得遍體鱗傷了
Yeah, but then we were battered by these waves 'cause Pink fought them.
‎你說過我們不該與大自然對抗
I mean, you said we shouldn't fight Mother Nature.
‎那我們就跟它合作
So let's work with her.
‎讓小粉去沖浪吧
Let Pink surf.
‎等等 她說得對
Wait, she's right.
‎如果站在海浪前 你會被擊倒
If you stand in front of the wave, it knocks you down,
‎但如果你去沖浪 就能踏浪而行
but if you surf with them, it doesn't.
‎大部分時候是這樣
Most of the time.
‎對 聽著 不使用浮錨
Yeah, look, without the drogue,
‎你要面對的是18米高的巨浪 杰絲
you're gonna be up against 60-foot waves, Jess.
‎所以不要被海浪沖擊
Yeah, so instead of getting battered by 'em,
‎而是乘浪而上
we'd ride over them.
‎小粉體型嬌小 正好是優勢
Pink being small would actually help.
‎小粉能撐得住嗎
Is Pink up to this?
‎你才剛補好艙壁上的裂縫 ‎它能堅持嗎
You only just patched that crack in the bulkhead. Will it hold?
‎況且你也筋疲力盡了 ‎而那風暴聽起來就像場馬拉松
You're also exhausted, Jessy, and the storm sounds like a marathon.
‎我不想功虧一簣
I'm so close.
‎嘿 別關心成敗了
Hey, don't worry about that.
‎現在活著回家更重要
Making it home alive is more important right now.
‎你必須靠岸
You're gonna have to pull in.
‎我同意本的說法 安全第一
I agree with Ben. Be safe.
‎不 穿過巴斯海峽
No! Cut through the straight.
‎-對 我喜歡這個選項 ‎-我喜歡沖浪那個
Yeah, I like that option. I like the surfer one.
‎-我猜你是支持“靠岸”嘍 爸爸  ‎-那個…
I'm guessing you vote for "pull in," Dad? Well…
‎對 顯然這是最保險的…
yeah, it's obviously the safest…
‎杰絲 我…
Oh, Jessy, uh…
‎我不知道 我真的不知道
I-- I don't know. I really don't.
‎我幾乎都沒出過海
I-- I barely sail offshore,
‎可是你呢 天吶 你環游了世界呀
but you, God, you've sailed around the world.
‎聽著 你了解海洋 你了解你的船
Look, you know the ocean, you know your boat.
‎我相信你的判斷
I trust that you know what's best.
‎你爸爸說得對
Your Dad's right.
‎你是那艘船的船長
You're the captain of that ship.
‎無論你做任何決定 我們都會支持你
We will support whatever decision you make.
‎謝謝你 爸爸 謝謝你 媽媽
Thanks, Dad. Thanks, Mum.
‎我愛你們
I love you.
‎我們愛你 杰絲
We love you, Jessy.
‎本 我的直覺告訴我 要穿過風暴群
Ben, my gut is telling me to go through these storms,
‎不使用浮錨
and I'm not gonna use the drogue.
‎這會是一場惡戰
It won't be easy.
‎你需要保持冷靜 忍受疲憊
You'll need to be calm, endure fatigue.
‎過程可能會持續幾天
It's gonna last days.
‎我知道
I know.
‎我能做到
I can do it.
‎我可以的 本
I've got this, Ben.
‎只要你自己想清楚后果
As long as you understand the consequences.
‎我明白
I do.
‎你說了算 船長
You're the captain, Captain.
‎（里奇之火 ‎優質披薩-新鮮烘焙）
‎-沃森的披薩  ‎-披薩
-Pizza for Watson! -Pizzas!
‎湯姆 能給我們透露更多信息嗎
Tom, can we get some more information, please?
‎湯姆 請說兩句
Tom, just a quick second.
‎大家都準備好了嗎  ‎好的 簡要陳述一下
Everyone right to go? Okay, brief statement.
‎杰絲會設法應對風暴
Jess will be tackling the storm,
‎繼續嘗試成為
continuing on in her attempt
‎獨自完成無間斷環球航海的 ‎最年輕人士
to become the youngest to sail… nonstop and unassisted around the world.
‎她絕對應該靠岸啊
Surely, she should pull in.
‎船長已經做出了她的決定 ‎不接受后續提問 謝謝
The captain has made her decision. No further questions, thank you.
‎漢娜
Hannah!
‎艾米莉 能簡短聲明一下嗎
Emily, can we get a quick statement, please? Emily?
‎（第198天 塔斯馬尼亞海岸 ‎離家2395公里）
‎澳洲人民已然目睹風暴席卷海岸線
Australians have seen particularly terrifying storms ravaging the coastlines.
‎而此刻杰西卡沃森的無間斷 ‎單人環球航海之旅 再經過一個海岬
The timing of the storm front is especially devastating for Jessica Watson,
‎就能大功告成 這場風暴的降臨 ‎恐將對其航海計劃
whose nonstop, solo, and unassisted circumnavigation
‎造成毀滅性的打擊
is one cape shy of being completed.
‎（歡迎加入水手行列 ‎本）
‎堅持住 船員們
Hold on, crew.
‎我們可以的 小粉
We got this, Pink!
‎嘿 本
Hey, Ben.
‎等壓線越來越靠近了
Isobars are getting close together.
‎這是什么意思
What does that mean?
‎單體風暴合而為一了
The storm cells have merged.
‎三個風暴前緣相遇 ‎合并成一個新的巨大風暴
The three fronts have morphed into one giant storm.
‎我們難以想象杰西卡此刻的感受
Now, one can only imagine how Jessica must be feeling right now
‎她即將面臨有生以來最艱巨的挑戰
as she's about to face her toughest challenge.
‎（第201天 塔斯馬尼亞海岸 ‎離家1912公里）
‎有一個外星人在天上等待
‎他想過來見我們
‎但害怕…
‎有一個外星人…
‎杰絲 我們都在
Jess, we're all here.
‎嘿
Hey. Hey!
‎跟我說說話吧 我需要分散注意力
Could you talk to me? I need distracting.
‎我喜歡蚯蚓
I love earthworms!
‎尼克
Nick!
‎那個男生叫尼克
Nick, the boy's name's Nick.
‎什么男生
Um, what boy? What boy?
‎萬一我沒抗過去呢
And what if I don't make it?
‎不可能 伙計
Not an option, mate.
‎告訴你 杰絲
Hey, tell you what, Jess.
‎只要你平安回來
You get back in one piece,
‎我就開著鮑伊號出海到悉尼迎接你
I'll take Bowie out of the docks and sail to Sydney to meet you.
‎成交嗎
Deal?
‎你會出海 到海上
You'll sail? Like, open waters?
‎對 我甚至可能會開回新西蘭老家 ‎但前提是你必須回來
Yeah, yeah, I might even sail home to New Zealand. But you gotta get here first.
‎行 好啊 成交
Yeah, okay. Deal.
‎杰絲 你還在嗎
Jessy? Jessy, you still there?
‎在 你之前不想讓我穿越風暴 ‎也許是有道理的
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah. Might've had a point not wanting me to do this, Dad.
‎我好害怕
I'm scared!
‎漢娜 我也怕
Oh. Oh, Hannah, me too.
‎但這是我自己的選擇 對嗎
But I chose to be here, yeah?
‎我選擇了走這一步 就絕不會后悔
I chose to be here and I'm never gonna regret it.
‎不入虎穴 焉得虎子 對吧
Nothing ventured, nothing gained, right?
‎（極端危險天氣警告）
‎-不可能 ‎-什么
-That's impossible. -What?
‎什么不可能 什么
What's impossible? What's impossible?
‎-快告訴我  ‎-杰絲
-What? Tell me, quick! -Jess!
‎好的 小粉 你做得很好
That's it, Pink. You're doing great.
‎拜托 停下
Please, stop!
‎求你放過它
Please, let her go!
‎杰絲
-Jess?
‎媽媽
Mum?
‎她的緊急警報觸發了
Her emergency alarm went off.
‎她在…
She's…
‎4點6米深的水下
15 feet underwater.
‎不
No.
‎不 她一定沒事的
No, she's all right.
‎打給她
Call her.
‎嘿 電話…
Hey, the phone…
‎電話在風暴中會沒信號 記得嗎
The phone loses signal in storms, remember?
‎只是打不通而已
-It's just the phone.
‎只是電話沒信號了
It's just the phone.
‎拜托 杰絲 接電話啊
C-C-Come on, Jess, answer.
‎好了
Okay.
‎-杰絲 杰絲 不要  ‎-別這樣 湯姆
-Jess! -Stop. -Jess, no! -Stop, Tom.
‎不
No!
‎我在呢
-I got you.
‎沒事的
It's all right.
‎-不 ‎-朱莉
-No. -Jules.
‎不…
No…
‎杰絲
Jess?
‎我們成功了
We made it.
‎小粉救了我
Pink saved me.
‎杰絲
Jess?
‎嗨 媽媽
Hi, Mum.
‎你不知道我聽見你的聲音有多開心
You don't know how good it is to hear your voice.
‎天啊
Oh, God.
‎我也是
Yours too.
‎天吶 你真該看看現在的天空
Oh, God, you should see the sky right now.
‎是嗎 很特別吧
Yeah? Pretty special?
‎非常特別
Really special.
‎你能快回來嗎 我等得花都謝了
Jess, can you come home already? You're aging me!
‎好
Yeah.
‎我想我準備好了
I think I'm ready.
‎她做到了
She did it.
‎她真的做到了 過來
She bloody did it! -Come here!
‎來抱抱
Come here!
‎你讓我們擔心死了 杰絲
You had us worried, Jessy.
‎-在拍嗎  ‎-是漢娜
-Are we rolling? -It's Hannah.
‎都準備好了嗎 攝影機就位了
Everyone ready? You got the shot?
‎杰絲成功穿越了風暴
Jess has made it through the storm.
‎沒有任何嚴重受傷或者損壞 ‎她目前正在回家的路上
She suffered no serious injuries or damage and is on her way home.
‎好了
-Yes! -All right.
‎好的 好了 各位 請離開草坪
All right. All right, all right, everyone, off the lawn!
‎我還指望它長點草呢
All right, I'm trying to grow it.
‎（第210天 悉尼港）
‎（杰西卡沃森 ‎歸家日）
‎逾八萬人蜂擁至悉尼港前灘
Over 80,000 people crowd Sydney Harbor foreshore
‎見證杰西卡沃森 這名女學生 ‎更準確地說 這位杰出的年輕女性
to see Jessica Watson, the schoolgirl, rather, the remarkable young woman
‎在出海210天后回家
arrive home after 210 days at sea,
‎她的壯舉讓世人 ‎看到了鼓舞人心的力量
a lesson in the power of inspiration,
‎這個勇敢的靈魂深深地震撼了
and the impact that one courageous soul
‎成千上萬的人
can have on so many,
‎包括我在內
including me.
‎來了
Here we go.
‎（官方終點線 2010年5月15日）
‎-3點33分 ‎-3點33分
-3:33. -3:33.
‎注意 準備播報 她到了 3點33分
Breaker, breaker, she's in. 3:33.
‎她成功了
She did it.
‎太好啦
Yeah!
‎杰絲
Jess!
‎杰西卡沃森穿過終點線
Jessica Watson crosses the line
‎歷經44448公里 完成了她的無間斷…
-Completing her nonstop… -after 24,000 nautical miles.
‎這里 快來看 看看這是誰
Here! Come, look! Look who's there!
‎是杰西卡
It's Jessica!
‎你回家了
You're home!
‎你真的回家了
You're really home!
‎有人想跟你打招呼
There's some people who want to say hi.
‎嘿 你做到了
-Oh! You got it.
‎杰絲
Hey! Jess!
‎-看那邊  ‎-來吧
-Look at that! -Come on!
‎歡迎回來 杰西卡 多么驚人的成就
Welcome back, Jessica. What a remarkable achievement.
‎你是我們國家的驕傲
You've done our nation proud.
‎你現在是澳大利亞最新的國民英雄了
You now stand tall as Australia's newest hero.
‎回家的感覺真好
It's so great to be home.
‎但我并不贊同 ‎總理先生剛才那番話 我不…
But I'm actually gonna disagree with what the prime minister just said, I don't…
‎我不認為自己是一個英雄
I don't consider myself a hero.
‎我只是一個相信夢想的平凡女孩
I'm just an ordinary girl who believed in her dream.
‎要完成這樣的事跡并不需要與眾不同
You don't have to be anyone special to achieve something like this,
‎只要找到自己的夢想 并堅信不移地
you just have to find your dream, believe in it,
‎為之努力奮斗就好
and work really hard.
‎感謝大家的熱情歡迎
Thank you for the amazing welcome.
‎（歡迎回家 杰西卡）
‎（2010年5月15日 ‎16歲的杰西卡沃森）
‎（在海上航行210天后 ‎返回澳大利亞）
‎（她在七次翻船中死里逃生 ‎經歷了逾21米高的巨浪）
‎（2011年1月 ‎杰西卡被提名為澳大利亞年度青年）
‎（盡管有閱讀障礙 ‎但她寫了兩本暢銷書）
‎（杰西卡至今仍是一名航海愛好者）
‎字幕翻譯：覃璇
‎（深切懷念卡梅隆戴爾）